http://www.mnswim.org/team/czmnlsc/page/governance1/policies-manuals--bylaws

Youtube
HomeAboutJoin MNswim!Mission & VisionMNSI Board & StaffPrivacy StatementPromotions PolicyRecognition & AwardsTeam MinnesotaClubsMN Find-A-ClubClub Development ProgramsPool Grant ProgramClub Resources & DocumentsAthletesAthletes CommitteeScholastic All-AmericanMN Records & Top TimesAthlete Resources & Documents2021 Olympic Trials QualifiersCoachesEmploymentCoach Resources & DocumentsLinks to Coach AssociationsWebinarsOfficialsSafe SportSafe Sport for AthletesSafe Sport for ParentsSafe Sport for CoachesMAAPP CenterSafe Sport Recognition ProgramTraining OpportunitiesReport a ConcernDiversity, Equity, & InclusionMeets/EventsUpcoming Meets & EventsZoning and StandingsTime StandardsMeet File Club Contact ListMeet Evaluations2020-21 Fall/Winter Meets Awarded2019-2020 Meet Planning CalendarCentral Zone Sanction Appeal PanelHosting MeetsMeet Director's ManualMeet Check-in FAQs and SheetsMeet Management DocumentsObserved Meet InfoDocuments/ResourcesGovernancePolicies, Manuals & BylawsAdministrative CalendarBoard of ReviewStaff & Board ContactsBOD Meetings & MinutesBudgetCommittees & MeetingsHouse of DelegatesStrategic PlanForm 990Crisis Communication Disaster RecoveryCOVID-19 HubUSA Swimming News
Minnesota Swimming—Policies, Manuals, and Bylaws
Policy Online Summary For archived/retired policies, click here
001 - Mission Statement 002 - By-Laws (restated April 2019; approval by USA Swimming July 2019) 100 MSI Organization 110 – National Convention 140 – Sanctioning Officer Authority 180 - Athlete Travel 200 Competition Guide 201 - Closed Meets  AMENDED (10/15/19) 202 – Conference Rules Exemptions 210A “C” Time Standards 220 – Meet Sanction 220A Meet Sanction Deposit 220B Meet Sanction Request 220C Protecting “A” Meets 220D Sanction Denial 220E - Meet Sanction/Approval Deadlines & Fees  AMENDED (7/21/20) 220F - Outstanding Balances 220G - Meet Engagement/Sanctioning -COVID-19 221 - Sanction Violations 231 –   Meet Fees AMENDED 11/17/20 233 – Deck Registration Surcharge  AMENDED (11/27/12) 234 – Time Trials Sanction Fee 234A - Time Trials   (AMENDED (11/15/16) 237 - Protest Fees 238A - Non Registered Swimmer Fines 239 - Seasonal Championship Splash Fees (AMENDED 10/17/17) 240 – Meet Information 240A – Distribution of Meet Information 240B – Change of Meet Information 241A – Order of Events 241B – Special Order of Events 241C – Relays in “A” Meets 241D - 800 Free Relay 241E - Senior Events 242– Entry Deadline 242A - No Times Entries 242B - Non conforming Entries 242C – Entries from Satellite Clubs 242D - Host Club Entries  AMENDED (4/15/14) 242E - Proof of Times for Championship Meets AMENDED (11/15/16) 243A – Seeding Distance Events AMENDED (11/21/13) 244 – 4 Hour Rule  AMENDED (11/21/13) 245 – 5 Hour Rule  AMENDED (11/21/13) 246 - Falsified Entries 248 - Relay Participation Limit  ADOPTED (01/15/13) 249 - Start Date to Accept Entries  ADOPTED (04/15/14) 250 – Warm-Ups  CORRECTION (10/15/13) 251 – Open Lanes  AMENDED (01/16/18) 252 – Flyover Starts 253 – Host Club Officials 254 – Meet Director 255 – Meet Marshals 256 – Volunteer Timers 257 - Scratch Rule 260 – Meet Awards 260A – Award Availability 262 – Best Time Ribbons 263 - ABC Finals Awards 264 - State Records 280 – Adaptive Swimming 281 – Adaptive Swimming Travel Reimbursement 290 - Meet Director's Manual 291 - Mask/Cloth Face Covering Protocol for Swim Meets
300 State Championships 302A – 10 and Under Relays 320 – Relays 321 – 800 Free Relays 321A - Eligibility for Finals
400 Age Group Programs 402 - Aging Up for Championship Meets AMENDED (12/18/16) 500 Senior Programs
600 Coaches and Officials 603 - Non-Athlete Member Check-In for Swim Meets 700 Clubs 701 - Annual Club registration Fee 800 Finance Policies 820 - Investment Policy 821 - Investment Policy Statement 840 - National Meet Financial Support 850 - Diversity Grants  860 - Funded Board Designated Operating Reserve 870 - Failed Electronic Payment Fines/Penalties
900 Miscellaneous 901 -  MSI Equipment REVISED (7/17/18) 903 -  Zone Scholarships 904 - Life Membership
Manuals
Note:  To fulfill the requirements for USA Swimming's LEAP Level 1 certification a compilation of MSI policies, rules and regulations were assembled into two manuals. The manuals are linked below.  Swim Meets: Rules and Regulations Originally compiled:  May 2011 Last saved: July 2020 Policies and Procedures Manual Originally compiled: August 2011 Last saved: May 2019
Bylaws amended and restated April 2019 Bylaws (.docx) Bylaws (.pdf)
Crisis Management/Disaster Recovery Plan The MNSI Crisis Management Plan manages the distribution of critical, often sensitive, information to the media, the public, and its members while the Disaster Recovery Plan is designed to insure business continuity by protecting the LSC from threats to its physical assets and IT-disabling disasters. See the plans here.
Zone Board of Review Effective January 1, 2015: Board of review inquiries from members of Minnesota Swimming, Inc. (MSI) can be directed to one of two boards: the Central Zone Board of Review or the National Board of Review.
To become more familiar about the areas of responsibility for each of the boards click here for more information.
Link to the procedure to file a Petition with the Central Zone Board of Review  January 2015
Link to the Central Zone Board of Review webpage
(NOTE: The Bylaws of MSI do not establish an administrative review board at the LSC level. According to USA Swimming this is optional and must be established by amendment to the Bylaws adopted by the MSI House of Delegates.)
Amateur Sports Act of 1978 The Ted Stevens Olympic and Amateur Sports Act of 1978, signed by President Jimmy Carter, establishes a United States Olympic Committee and provides for national governing bodies for each Olympic sport. The Act provides important legal protection for individual athletes.
The Act charters the U.S. Olympic Committee, which in turn can charter a national governing body (NGB) for each sport such as USA Swimming for competitive swimming. Each NGB in turn establishes the rules for selecting the United States Olympic Team and promotes amateur competition in that sport. The Act requires that active athletes (defined as amateur athletes who have represented the United States in international amateur competition within the last ten years) must hold 20 percent of the voting power of any board or committee in an NGB.
The Act also provides athletes with due process and appeal rights concerning eligibility disputes.
Promotions Policy To see our Promotions Policy, click here.
Privacy Statement To see our Privacy Statement, click here.
Facebook
Twitter
Instagram
Youtube
© Copyright SportsEngine, Inc. This website is powered by TeamUnify but is owned by and subject to the Organization’s privacy policy.
© Copyright SportsEngine, Inc. This website is powered by GoMotion but is owned by and subject to the Organization’s privacy policy.
Privacy Statement
